

"I am a budding Junior Developer with a passion for clean code, learning new concepts, data-mining, front-end development and process-automation. Before switiching to development, I worked long and hard in the Communications Branch of the Military, followed by the Geospatial Industry. My education background was in Physics and GIS before joining a development bootcamp recently. I seek to grow as a developer so that I can become a specialist in GIS Development. On my own, I draw, read essays, write articles, and go on long hikes."

DEVELOPMENT - BRIANBANCROFT.CA

Examples of projects available at brianbancroft.ca include:

NODE POSTGIS KOA Get mv MP - Backend

UK Crime Webmap - Frontend JS AJAX

Map Georeferencing - Backend PYTHON ARCGIS

EXPERIENCE

Oct 2014 -Mar 2016

Field Controller, Sight Surveillance

Field-based mapping and radio management

- Created daily-changing operational maps for an oil and gas projects using ArcGIS
- Worked alone to maintain and troubleshoot to a large radio network used by field operators in a Winter Drilling or emergency response environment
- Tracked, monitored and carried out analysis on individuals using a real-time GPS position feed provided from the above radios

Jan 2014 -May 2014

Library Technician, University of Ottawa, Geographical Statistical and Government Center

Front-end client service and support for library users, special projects in support of subject librarians

- Automation of large-scale georeferencing and file preparation for online distribution using Python
- · Assistance with students and university staff in seeking and acquiring data through multiple sources

Nov 2012 -Sept 2013

Geophysicist's Assistant, Natural Resources Canada (FSWEP)

Carrying out research and field tasks under direct supervision of a Geophysicst researcher

- Magneteotelluric modelling, writing results and providing advice based on results
- Drafting and submitting results successfully through a peer-review process (Open File 7549)

EDUCATION

Sept 2009 -Dec 2013

Hon B.Sc, Double Major (Physics, Geomatics)

University of Ottawa

Cartography, Databases, Linear Algebra, Multivariable Calculus, Differentials, Particle Mechanics, Waves and Optics, Electrodynamics, Thermodynamics, Geomorphology, Natural Resource Management, Impact Assessments, Geospatial Problem-Solving

Web Bootcamp

Mar 2016 -May 2016

Lighthouse Labs Toronto (May 2016, 2 months)

Ruby, Javascript, Front-End Development, AngularJS, Backend Development,

Rails, node.js. AJAX, API's, object-oriented programming, recursion.

CERTIFICATION, AWARDS

Chief Scout's Award, 1999 Canadian Forces Decoration, 2013 ESRI Certification - Desktop Associate, 2016